const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following can cause inhibition of action potential?","answers":[{"option":"Influx of potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Influx of chloride","bool":true},{"option":"Influx of bicarbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Influx of calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Influx of sodium","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of pyogenic osteomyelitis?","answers":[{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following is the longest muscle in the human body?","answers":[{"option":"Pectineus","bool":false},{"option":"Iliacus","bool":false},{"option":"Psoas major","bool":false},{"option":"Vastus medialis","bool":false},{"option":"Sartorius","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following types of cells do Howship's lacunae contain?","answers":[{"option":"Osteoblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Osteocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Chondrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoprogenitor cells","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoclasts","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following is the keystone of the medial longitudinal arch of the foot?","answers":[{"option":"Navicular bone","bool":false},{"option":"Talus head","bool":true},{"option":"Calcaneal tubercle","bool":false},{"option":"Medial cuneiform bone","bool":false},{"option":"Metatarsals","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Injury to which of the following nerve causes winging of the scapula?","answers":[{"option":"Long thoracic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Nerve to subclavius","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pectoral nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal scapular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Medial pectoral nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A football player gets hit on the lateral aspect of his knee joint, resulting in a fracture of the neck of the fibula. Which of the following nerves is most likely to be injured in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial fibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Tibial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Common peroneal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Deep fibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sciatic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"What is chondroitin sulfate made of?","answers":[{"option":"N-acetylgalactosamine + glucuronic acid","bool":true},{"option":"N-acetylglucosamine + iduronic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Glucuronic acid+ iduronic acid","bool":false},{"option":"N-acetylglucosamine + glucuronic acid","bool":false},{"option":"N-acetylgalactosamine + iduronic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Nernst equation describes the relationship of diffusion potential to which of the following across a semipermeable membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Counter transport","bool":false},{"option":"Concentration of multiple ions","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Concentration of a single ion","bool":true},{"option":"Co-transport","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Against which of the following are autoantibodies produced in Lambert-Eaton syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Presynaptic calcium channels","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine channels","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle proteins","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which muscle unlocks the knee joint?","answers":[{"option":"Quadriceps femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Plantaris","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrocnemius","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteus","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Damage to which nerve presents as the claw hand?","answers":[{"option":"Radial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Median nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Musculocutaneous nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Cyclones are classified as which type of disasters?","answers":[{"option":"Telluric and tectonic","bool":false},{"option":"Accident","bool":false},{"option":"Atomic explosion","bool":false},{"option":"Topological","bool":false},{"option":"Meteorological","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"In a patient, the iliopsoas is found paralyzed. Which of the following muscle will undergo hypertrophy to compensate for hip flexion?","answers":[{"option":"Pectineus","bool":false},{"option":"Vastus intermedius","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor fascia latae","bool":true},{"option":"Rectus femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Semimembranosus","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following anatomical descriptions can help a surgeon to harvest a part of a great saphenous vein for grafting?","answers":[{"option":"It lies anterior to the medial condyle of the femur","bool":false},{"option":"It lies posterior to medial malleolus","bool":false},{"option":"It passes deep to the fascia lata of the thigh","bool":false},{"option":"It originates from the femoral vein","bool":false},{"option":"It passes superficial to the fascia lata of thigh","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"What is the mechanism of action of methylxanthine?","answers":[{"option":"Beta-adrenergic receptor stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-adrenergic receptor stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Regulation of intracellular fluoride levels","bool":false},{"option":"Regulation of intracellular sodium levels","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of phosphodiesterase","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Cartilages are made up of which type of collagen fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Type 4","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1","bool":false},{"option":"Type 6","bool":false},{"option":"Type 3","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"During skeletal muscle contraction, when the myosin heads bind to actin, the Fenn effect occurs. Which of the following correctly describes this phenomenon?","answers":[{"option":"Work done is inversely proportional to ATP cleaved","bool":false},{"option":"Work done is directly proportional to ATP cleaved","bool":true},{"option":"Work done is directly proportional to ATP and Mg2+ cleaved","bool":false},{"option":"Work done is inversely proportional to ATP and Mg2+ cleaved","bool":false},{"option":"Work done is directly proportional to  Ca2+ cleaved","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A woman comes in with the complaint of being unable to climb stairs. Which muscle is most likely to be weakened?","answers":[{"option":"Piriformis","bool":false},{"option":"Gluteus maximus","bool":true},{"option":"Gluteus medius","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator externus","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Collagen synthesis requires hydroxylation of lysine and proline residues. Which of the following is necessary as a cofactor for this hydroxylation?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin E","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following enzymes is deficient in the Hurler syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha-L-iduronidase","bool":true},{"option":"Iduronate-2-sulfatase","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin sulfamidase","bool":false},{"option":"N-acetyl-glucosaminidase","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-glucuronidase","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"What is a term used for continuous, sustained contraction with no relaxation?","answers":[{"option":"Incomplete tetanus","bool":false},{"option":"Treppe","bool":false},{"option":"Wave summation","bool":false},{"option":"Complete tetanus","bool":true},{"option":"Twitch","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which nerve supplies the teres major muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Lower subscapular nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Radial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Upper subscapular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Suprascapular nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"What is the velocity of the action potential through the skeletal muscle?","answers":[{"option":"2-3 mm/s","bool":false},{"option":"20-30 m/s","bool":false},{"option":"2-3 m/s","bool":false},{"option":"3-4 m/s","bool":true},{"option":"1-2 m/s","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A 67-year-old man develops bow legs and pain over a period of 5 years, and progressive hearing loss over a period of 2 years. Bone biopsy shows a mosaic pattern. Serum electrolyte patterns are normal. What is the patient suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Bone deformities","bool":true},{"option":"Giant cell tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Chalk stick fracture","bool":false},{"option":"High output cardiac function","bool":false},{"option":"Neurological symptoms","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the contents of the cubital fossa?","answers":[{"option":"All the superficial veins are deep into the cutaneous nerve","bool":false},{"option":"The radial nerve is on the lateral side","bool":true},{"option":"The median nerve is lateral to the brachial artery","bool":false},{"option":"The ulnar nerve is on the medial side","bool":false},{"option":"The brachial artery is lateral to the tendon of biceps brachii","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A gunshot wound at the axilla severely injures the posterior cord of the brachial plexus. Which of the following muscles would be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Rhomboid major","bool":false},{"option":"Deltoid","bool":true},{"option":"Bicep brachii","bool":false},{"option":"Pronator teres","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavius","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A 35-year-old male was referred from an orthopedic out-patient department with intermittent locking of the right knee. He was evaluated with an anteroposterior and lateral view of the knee joint which showed a normal appearance of the knee joint with no loose body. Which additional view can be used to identify the loose body?","answers":[{"option":"Anteroposterior weight bearing view","bool":false},{"option":"Skyline view","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal beam lateral view","bool":false},{"option":"Tunnel view","bool":true},{"option":"Oblique view","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"What is the diffusion potential that inhibits the net diffusion of a particular ion across the membrane called?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibitory postsynaptic potential","bool":false},{"option":"Action potential","bool":false},{"option":"Postsynaptic potential","bool":false},{"option":"Graded potential","bool":false},{"option":"Nernst potential","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A man is referred to the outpatient department with no extension of proximal and middle phalanges of the 4th and 5th digits. He also has a thickening of palmar aponeurosis and digital slips. What is the proximal attachment of the thickening?","answers":[{"option":"Flexor digitorum profundus","bool":false},{"option":"Palmaris longus","bool":true},{"option":"Flexor digitorum superficialis","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor policis longus","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor carpi ulnaris","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A man’s medial superficial inguinal lymph nodes are enlarged. Where will these lymph nodes be found?","answers":[{"option":"Skin of leg","bool":false},{"option":"Skin of thigh","bool":false},{"option":"Rectum","bool":false},{"option":"Groin","bool":true},{"option":"Penis","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Osteoclasts are bone cells with which of the following properties?","answers":[{"option":"Housed as isogenous cells in lacunae","bool":true},{"option":"They communicate through gap junctions","bool":false},{"option":"They give rise to osteophytes","bool":false},{"option":"They are immature cells","bool":false},{"option":"They contain large amount of rough endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which type of junction protein is not important for cell adhesion?","answers":[{"option":"Calmodulin","bool":true},{"option":"Cadherin","bool":false},{"option":"Integrins","bool":false},{"option":"Selectins","bool":false},{"option":"Cell adhesion molecules (CAMs)","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which muscles are the flexors of the elbow joint?","answers":[{"option":"Anconeus and brachioradialis","bool":false},{"option":"Brachialis and anconeus","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps brachii and brachialis","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Coracobrachialis and brachialis","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Skeletal muscle contraction is initiated by the neuromuscular junction. What is the first step in this process of skeletal muscle contraction?","answers":[{"option":"Binding of calcium with the neurotransmitter vesicles","bool":false},{"option":"Arrival of action potential to the axon terminal","bool":true},{"option":"Excitation of the postsynaptic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of the presynaptic calcium channel","bool":false},{"option":"Release of neurotransmitter acetylcholine","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A patient comes to the outpatient department with a fracture of the upper part of the femur. Which of the following structures will not be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Quadrate tubercle","bool":false},{"option":"Head of the femur","bool":false},{"option":"Neck of the femur","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor tubercle","bool":true},{"option":"Intertrochanteric line","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Smooth muscle contraction begins with calcium binding to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Calmodulin","bool":true},{"option":"Tropomyosin","bool":false},{"option":"Myosin","bool":false},{"option":"Actin","bool":false},{"option":"Troponin","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which nerve is damaged in a fracture of the surgical neck of the humerus?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal scapular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Radial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Median nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following features of compact bone is different from that of a spongy bone?","answers":[{"option":"It has a Haversian system","bool":true},{"option":"Thoracic skeleton is made up from this","bool":false},{"option":"Lines medullary cavity","bool":false},{"option":"It is also called cancellous bone","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial bones are made up from this","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"What marks the end of the action potential peak?","answers":[{"option":"Opening of Na+ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Closing of Ca2+ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Closing of K+ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of Ca2+ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Closing of Na+ channels","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following is a characteristic of renal osteodystrophy due to hyperparathyroidism?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic hypophosphatemia and hypocalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Normal vitamin D3 level","bool":false},{"option":"Hypocalcemia and hyperphosphatemia","bool":true},{"option":"Normal serum phosphatase level","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased serum alkaline phosphatase","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Microscopically, compact bone contains an osteon or Haversian system comprising the Haversian canal and lamellae containing a matrix with collagen. Which type of collagen does compact bone have?","answers":[{"option":"Type VII","bool":false},{"option":"Type I","bool":true},{"option":"Type IV","bool":false},{"option":"Type II","bool":false},{"option":"Type III","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A young medical student went to the outpatient department to check on a 50-year-old patient. He introduced himself as a doctor and prescribed some medicines. He was super proud of his achievement and told his teacher about it, who disapproved of his behavior. What was the reason for the disapproval of the teacher?","answers":[{"option":"He was proud on his wrong treatment","bool":false},{"option":"He did not follow the medical ethic","bool":false},{"option":"He did not explain the patient’s disease","bool":false},{"option":"He discussed it with his teacher","bool":false},{"option":"He introduced himself as a doctor","bool":true}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"An action potential arrives at a muscle. The muscle would get depolarized when which of the following ions moves through the membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Ca+2","bool":false},{"option":"Na+","bool":true},{"option":"Cl-","bool":false},{"option":"K+","bool":false},{"option":"Mg+2","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following is a property of skeletal muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Elasticity","bool":true},{"option":"Rhythmicity","bool":false},{"option":"Syncytium","bool":false},{"option":"Latch system","bool":false},{"option":"Self-excitation","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"The scapula is formed by which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Neural crest cells","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic lateral plate mesoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Paraxial mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Splanchnic lateral plate mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Axial mesoderm","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"The resting membrane potential of the membrane is -90 mv. What causes the -86 mv?","answers":[{"option":"Voltage gated Na+ channels","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Leaky Na+ and K+ channels","bool":true},{"option":"Voltage gated Ca2+ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Na+-K+ pump","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most accurate statement?","answers":[{"option":"Upper limb buds are evident earlier than lower limb buds","bool":true},{"option":"Limbs of different mammals are different","bool":false},{"option":"Apical ectodermal ridge (AER) has a negative effect","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Limb buds become visible in the sixth week of development","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"The muscles of the posterior compartment of the thigh are attached to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Linea aspera","bool":false},{"option":"Medial condyle","bool":false},{"option":"Ishiopubic ramus","bool":false},{"option":"Ischial tuberosity","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"After an injury to the right foot, a person cannot dorsiflex his foot. This is due to damage to which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Saphenous nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Deep peroneal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Tibial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sural nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial peroneal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A patient has lung cancer and is told by the doctor to undergo a pulmonary biopsy and resection for treatment. The patient does not believe that he has lung cancer and does not want to undergo surgery even though the physician tells the patient about the low mortality rate of the surgery. What should the physician do?","answers":[{"option":"Give him weekly visits and encourage him to seek a second opinion","bool":true},{"option":"Force him to undergo surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Detain him and have a meeting with the board","bool":false},{"option":"Inform his family and relatives","bool":false},{"option":"Threaten him if he refuses to have his surgery","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"What type of disaster is a bushfire?","answers":[{"option":"Tectonic disaster","bool":false},{"option":"Meteorological disaster","bool":false},{"option":"Topographical hazard","bool":false},{"option":"Biological disaster","bool":false},{"option":"Natural disaster","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"The posterior cords of the brachial plexus are named according to their position relative to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Axillary artery","bool":true},{"option":"Brachial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis minor muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis major muscle","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following does not shorten or change during muscle contraction?","answers":[{"option":"I-Band","bool":false},{"option":"H-band","bool":false},{"option":"Z-line","bool":false},{"option":"A-Band","bool":true},{"option":"Sarcomere","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"The collagen superfamily consists of 25 types. Which of the following is the most abundant type of collagen?","answers":[{"option":"1","bool":true},{"option":"5","bool":false},{"option":"2","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"4","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"For routine blood sample collection of a patient, the nurse selects a vein present superficially, in the subcutaneous tissue overlying the cubital fossa, in front of the bicipital aponeurosis. Which of the following vein is being used for venipuncture?","answers":[{"option":"Median vein","bool":false},{"option":"Basilic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Median cubital vein","bool":true},{"option":"Axillary vein","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalic vein","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following is true about the brachial plexus?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"The dorsal scapular nerve originates from the trunk of the brachial plexus","bool":false},{"option":"The roots divide behind the second part of the axillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"The roots of the brachial plexus originate behind the scalene muscles","bool":false},{"option":"The medial and lateral pectoral nerves have no cutaneous branches","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A patient after recovery from the fracture of the fibula complains of inversion of the foot. Diagnosis of paralysis of peroneus longus muscle is made due to compression of the tendon of paralyzed muscle attached to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cuboid","bool":false},{"option":"Calcaneus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral cuneiform","bool":false},{"option":"Talus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial cuneiform","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A female patient is brought to the emergency department. X-ray findings show a fracture of the femoral neck and avascular necrosis of the femoral head. This is most likely a consequence of interruption to the blood supply to the head of the femur. What is the source of blood supply to the femoral head?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Tibial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior gluteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator artery","bool":false},{"option":"Branches from the profunda femoris artery","bool":true}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Outward rotation of the leg with the knee semi-flexed is a function of which muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Semitendinosus","bool":false},{"option":"Gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps femoris","bool":true},{"option":"Semimembranosus","bool":false},{"option":"Sartorius","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"In Paget disease, the activity of osteoblasts is determined by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bone alkaline phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Serum calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Bone calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Serum alkaline phosphatase","bool":true},{"option":"Serum phosphorus","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A person is having pain and tenderness in the left ankle joint. Which structure is most likely to be ruptured?","answers":[{"option":"Deltoid ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior cruciate ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cruciate ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Medial ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A patient loses flexion and lateral rotation at the hip joint. Which muscle is injured?","answers":[{"option":"Hamstring","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Gluteus maximus","bool":false},{"option":"Sartorius","bool":true},{"option":"Gluteus minimus","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Full knee flexion and full hip extension cannot be achieved simultaneously due to which of the following reasons?","answers":[{"option":"Shortening of the rectus femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Rotation of tibia","bool":false},{"option":"Shortening of the hamstrings","bool":true},{"option":"Rotation of fibula","bool":false},{"option":"Shortening of the gastrocnemius","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following organelles is characterized by the presence of cisternae and T-tubules?","answers":[{"option":"Lysosomes","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcolemma","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoplasmic reticulum","bool":true},{"option":"Smooth endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Rough endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"The saphenous vein is grafted in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Thrombophlebitis","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Varicose vein","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary occlusive disease","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertensive disease","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"From where are infusions mostly given into the saphenous vein?","answers":[{"option":"Foot","bool":false},{"option":"Ankle","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Knee","bool":false},{"option":"Thigh","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"The ventral and lateral flexor muscles of the vertebral column are derived from which of the following myotomes?","answers":[{"option":"Epaxial division","bool":false},{"option":"Sacrococcygeal","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic","bool":true},{"option":"Lumbar","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Median nerve compression arises between the two heads of a forearm muscle. This muscle also forms the medial border of the cubital fossa. What is the name of this muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Brachioradialis","bool":false},{"option":"Pronator teres","bool":true},{"option":"Biceps brachii","bool":false},{"option":"Brachialis","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A pregnant woman undergoes an ultrasound and finds out that her baby's right upper limb has not developed. It is concluded that the deformity is due to an abnormality in mesenchymal cells. Where do these abnormal mesenchymal cells belong?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral plate mesoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Intermediate mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Paraxial mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Notochord","bool":false},{"option":"Prochordal plate","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"In a geriatric clinic, old people are screened for diabetes. Which type of prevention is this?","answers":[{"option":"Primary","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial","bool":false},{"option":"Tertiary","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary","bool":true},{"option":"Quaternary","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which structure is most anterior in the popliteal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Popliteal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Tibial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sciatic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Common peroneal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Vitamin D is required for the mineralization of bone and its deficiency in growing individuals could lead to bowing of legs and knocking of knees. What is this defect known as?","answers":[{"option":"Paget’s disease of bone","bool":false},{"option":"Osteomalacia","bool":false},{"option":"Osteopetrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Rickets","bool":true},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"While observing a knee joint, a resident orthopedist noticed a groove between the lateral epicondyle of the femur and the tibial articular surface. Which muscle is attached to this groove?","answers":[{"option":"Gastrocnemius","bool":false},{"option":"Plantaris","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteus","bool":true},{"option":"Adductor magnus","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps femoris","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A person comes to the outpatient department with pain in his middle finger. The doctor finds pus present between the third and fifth metacarpals beneath the palmar aponeurosis. What is this space known as?","answers":[{"option":"Pulp","bool":false},{"option":"Thenar space","bool":false},{"option":"Midpalmar space","bool":true},{"option":"Palm crease","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothenar space","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A 20-year-old man comes to the emergency department after a motorbike accident. Due to the accident, the greater trochanter of his femur is damaged. Which muscle attaches to this structure?","answers":[{"option":"Iliacus","bool":false},{"option":"Gluteus maximus","bool":false},{"option":"Psoas major","bool":false},{"option":"Psoas minor","bool":false},{"option":"Gluteus minimus","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A man comes to the outpatient department with chronic liver disease. On examination, it is found that his ring and little fingers are flexed and there is a thickening of the palmar aponeurosis. Which muscle attaches to the aponeurosis?","answers":[{"option":"Flexor digitorum superficialis","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor carpi ulnaris","bool":false},{"option":"Palmaris longus","bool":true},{"option":"Flexor carpi radialis","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor digitorum profundus","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"When the forearm is flexed such that it is 90º to the arm and, whilst keeping it in the mid-prone position, further flexing it against resistance, a muscle is made prominently visible below the elbow. What muscle is visible below the elbow?","answers":[{"option":"Pronator quadratus","bool":false},{"option":"Teres major","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps brachii","bool":false},{"option":"Brachioradialis","bool":true},{"option":"Triceps brachii","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A 41-year-old patient loses sensation on the anterior and lateral sides of his thigh, down to his knee. A nerve that laterally passes under the inguinal ligament might be damaged. What could this nerve be?","answers":[{"option":"Sciatic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral cutaneous nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Medial cutaneous nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cutaneous nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Pes anserine bursa is associated with insertion of which of the following muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Semimembranosus, semitendinosus, bicep femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Gracilis, semitendinosus, semimembranosus","bool":false},{"option":"Sartorius, gracilis, semimembranosus","bool":false},{"option":"Sartorius, gracilis, semitendinosus","bool":true},{"option":"Vastus medialis, vastus intermedius, vastus lateralis","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"The unhappy triad of the knee is made up of the rupture of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cruciate ligament, medial meniscus, lateral collateral ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cruciate ligament, medial meniscus, lateral collateral ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Medial collateral ligament, medial meniscus, lateral collateral ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cruciate ligament, medial meniscus, medial collateral ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cruciate ligament, medial meniscus, medial collateral ligament","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"What are the strong bundles of fibers attaching the periosteum to the bone?","answers":[{"option":"Sharpey fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Reticular fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Elastic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Lamellar fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"What is the change in pattern of disease which affects the level and character of mortality in a population called?","answers":[{"option":"Disease transmission","bool":false},{"option":"Demographic transition","bool":false},{"option":"Epidemiological transition","bool":true},{"option":"Level transmission","bool":false},{"option":"Character transition","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which artery is the most unlikely to be damaged upon injury to the snuffbox?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsalis pollicis arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar artery","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal carpal branch of radial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Radial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Origin of the cephalic vein","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following will not be responsible for arm abduction from 0° to 180°?","answers":[{"option":"Intact radial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Initiation by supraspinatus","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezius muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Deltoid fibres","bool":false},{"option":"Intact axillary nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A 10-year-old boy continuously complained about having pain in his navicular bone. Upon examination, the physician found a shortening of the Achilles tendon and flattened medial longitudinal arch. What deformity could be related to this?","answers":[{"option":"Club foot","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral deformity","bool":false},{"option":"Pes cavus","bool":false},{"option":"Equinis","bool":false},{"option":"Pes planus","bool":true}]},{"id":86,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A patient presents to the emergency room with a fracture of the shaft of the humerus. It is a closed fracture with no observable injury to the radial nerve. What is the best method for stabilizing the bone?","answers":[{"option":"Plate fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Open reduction","bool":false},{"option":"Functional brace","bool":true},{"option":"Kocher's technique","bool":false},{"option":"Sling","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A patient is on corticosteroid therapy. Which of the following bone disorders can arise due to it?","answers":[{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteocystic fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Paget disease","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":true}]},{"id":88,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A 35-year-old pregnant woman has chronic renal disease. Which of the following bone disorders she is likely to develop?","answers":[{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pagets bone disease","bool":false},{"option":"Rickets","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteomalacia","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following factors contributes least to the stability of the glenohumeral joint?","answers":[{"option":"Coracohumeral ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Ball and socket","bool":true},{"option":"Glenohumeral ligaments","bool":false},{"option":"Coracoacromial ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrous capsule","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Fracture of the radial neck may lead to damage to which of the following arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Axillary","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar","bool":false},{"option":"Radial","bool":true},{"option":"Subclavian","bool":false},{"option":"Brachial","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which structure does not pass deep through the extensor retinaculum?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior tibial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Tibial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Tibialis anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Extensor digitorum longus tendon","bool":false},{"option":"Extensor hallucis tendon","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Both osteoporosis and osteopenia are the results of a decrease in bone mass. What is the similarity between them?","answers":[{"option":"Mosaic pattern histology","bool":false},{"option":"Both are bone mass at least 2.5 standard deviations below the mean peak bone mass","bool":false},{"option":"The most common causes are senile and post menopause","bool":true},{"option":"Senile high turnover variant","bool":false},{"option":"Most cases are secondary","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"What type of junctional complexes are present between 2 osteocytic processes?","answers":[{"option":"Desmosomes","bool":false},{"option":"Zonula adherens","bool":false},{"option":"Gap junctions","bool":true},{"option":"Tight junctions","bool":false},{"option":"Macula adherens","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Damage to the brachial plexus results in an upper limb that is medially rotated and adducted, with the elbow remaining in an extended position. What type of palsy is this?","answers":[{"option":"Ape hand","bool":false},{"option":"Claw hand","bool":false},{"option":"Erb's palsy","bool":true},{"option":"Wrist drop","bool":false},{"option":"Klumpke's palsy","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"There is a loss of sensation between the first and second toes. It is due to injury to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial peroneal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Common peroneal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sural nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Tibial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Deep peroneal nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":96,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following approaches should be used by a physician when interacting with patients?","answers":[{"option":"Apathetic approach","bool":false},{"option":"Pathetic approach","bool":false},{"option":"Judgmental approach","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic approach","bool":false},{"option":"Empathetic approach","bool":true}]},{"id":97,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A 25-year-old woman comes to the clinic and is requesting to terminate her pregnancy. What would be the best approach to deal with her concerns?","answers":[{"option":"Do not impose your beliefs or views on her","bool":true},{"option":"Tell her it is against your religion","bool":false},{"option":"Tell her it is against her religion","bool":false},{"option":"Do not respond","bool":false},{"option":"Call her parents or guardians","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"In a clinical setting, which of the following is true for a patient?","answers":[{"option":"Consent would not matter","bool":false},{"option":"Can withdraw from consent anytime","bool":true},{"option":"Cannot withdraw from consent after treatment","bool":false},{"option":"Has to give consent under every circumstance","bool":false},{"option":"Has to ask someone else for consent","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which structure is damaged in Klumpke's paralysis?","answers":[{"option":"Brachial plexus","bool":true},{"option":"Sacral plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Musculocutaneous nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Radial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Median nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"A patient presents to the emergency room with a fracture to his femur. Which of the following muscles does not attach to the femur?","answers":[{"option":"Gracillis","bool":true},{"option":"Vastus medialis","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor brevis","bool":false},{"option":"Vastus lateralis","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor longus","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which type of cartilage is the most likely to be calcified?","answers":[{"option":"Elastic","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed","bool":false},{"option":"Articular","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrocartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaline","bool":true}]},{"id":102,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which is correct for skeletal muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Sarcoplasmic reticulum provides ATP","bool":false},{"option":"They do not have cross-striations","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondria are a store house of Ca⁺²","bool":false},{"option":"T-tubule transfers action potential to the center of muscle fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Ca⁺²-calmodulin complex binds to actin filament","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"What is the most common treatable cause of visual impairment in old age?","answers":[{"option":"Macular degeneration","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic retinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertensive retinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Senile cataracts","bool":true}]},{"id":104,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2021","question":"Which of the following vaccines should be given to the elderly?","answers":[{"option":"Influenza","bool":true},{"option":"MMR","bool":false},{"option":"BCG","bool":false},{"option":"HIV","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis B","bool":false}]}]
export default arr